Aishwarya Dhore

Senior Java Full Stack Developer

As a dedicated and forward-thinking professional with 6 Years of experience, I am currently pursuing a Master of Science in Computer Engineering at the esteemed University of Arkansas.

Bentonville, Arkansas +1 2409363429 dhoreaishwarya47@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/aish warya-dhore https://github.com/aishwarya

EXPERIENCE

T-Systems ICT India Pvt Ltd, Pune-Full stack Senior Developer

Telecom and Routing(September 2022 - July 2023)

- Developed and optimized ESim support, ensuring a seamless transition from iPhone to Google Phone for customers.
- Developed and optimized location-based service APIs for precise SIM card tracking, enhancing efficiency for government services.
- Led the design and development of scalable cloud microservices for telecom routing services, ensuring seamless eSIM support across devices, including iPhone and Google.
- Implemented observability solutions using tools like Grafana to monitor and track system performance, enhancing the efficiency of location-based services for SIM card tracking.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to influence **architecture** and ensure seamless integration of services across multiple systems.
- Utilized CI/CD pipelines (Jenkins, Docker) for continuous integration and deployment, reducing deployment time by 40%.
- Played a crucial role in **debugging production issues**, ensuring system stability and integrity across multiple levels of the stack.
- A strong proponent of the Agile Methodology and an Agile Evangelist.

TIAA Global Business, Pune-Full stack Developer

Retirement Advisor (April 2021 - September 2022)

- Designed and developed **cloud-native microservices** using **Spring Boot** to enhance resource management solutions within the professional services domain.
- Migrated structured databases to **MongoDB** using **Talend**, improving data integration and accommodating evolving business needs.
- Led architectural discussions to implement scalable system designs aligned with business objectives, improving API performance and ensuring high availability.
- Developed a user-facing **Angular portal** for retired users, enabling efficient portfolio management with a focus on user experience.
- Built **test suites** for functional, regression, and UAT testing, and Integration testing ensuring system quality and stability before production releases.

SKILLS

JAVA, Spring Boot, Golang, HTML, CSS, REST APIs, Kubernetes, AWS, GCP, MySQL, MongoDB, Hibernate, Docker, Angular, Kafka, Microservice Architecture, Data structure and algorithms, React, Jenkins, NodeJS, Junit, Redis, ElasticSearch

EDUCATION

University Of Arkansas, Fayetteville - Master of Science, Computer Engineering

August 2023 - December 2024

Courses: Artificial Intelligence,
Data Mining, Computer
Security, Machine Learning,
Privacy Enhancing Technology,
Advance DBMS, Computer
Vision, Algorithms, Computer
Forensics, Graph and
Combinatorics

Dr. D.Y.Patil Institute of Engineering, Pimpri, Pune- B.E Computer Engineering

August 2014 - May 2017

Score: 75%

Hitachi Vantara, Pune— Cloud Engineer

Managed Cloud Services (March 2019 - April 2021)

- Engineered an application to optimize cloud infrastructure costs by 60%, leveraging AWS and CIS compliance standards to enhance cloud security by 98%.
- Led the design and development of CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins and Docker, improving deployment processes and ensuring system reliability through containerization.
- Designed and implemented Kubernetes clusters for microservices deployment, enhancing scalability and resilience in cloud environments.
- Implemented Kafka pipelines to process data from cloud platforms like AWS, providing real-time insights into resource usage and performance.
- Created APIs to enable seamless data integration and communication between microservices, ensuring robust and efficient system operations.

Neeyamo Enterprise Solution, Pune-Associate Product Developer

Buzzer (June 2017 - January 2019)

- Developed and maintained multiple applications, including a ticket-raising system and time-and-attendance system, using Spring Boot and Java, streamlining client and internal processes.
- Led the design of a widget-based application, consolidating functionality across multiple screens to enhance user experience and usability.
- Played a key role in **architecture discussions**, collaborating with senior stakeholders to ensure system designs aligned with business needs.
- Conducted **code reviews** and provided architectural guidance to junior team members to maintain high development standards.

University of Arkansas, Fayetteville- Graduate Teaching Assistant

Operating Systems(August 2023)

- Contributed to designing assignments for students and development of course material and supplementary resources.
- Conducted thorough grading of assignments, exams and assessments and provided constructive feedback.
- Led weekly discussion sessions and tutorials, fostering student engagement and participation. Mentored students particularly those facing challenges..

Y.B.Patil Polytechnic, Akurdi —Diploma in Computer Engineering

June 2011 - June 2014

Score: 80%

AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS

- Oracle Certified Professional, Java 7 SE.
- Platinum award for excellent performance at Hitachi Vantara
- Certified Skier
- Google Project Management Certified
- Advanced Algorithmic
 Thinking with Python
- Advanced Java Programming
- Deploying and Running Apache Kafka on Kubernetes
- Spring with GraphQL
- Generative AI
- Advance skill in Deep Learning and Neural Networks